Guide to the ILGWU. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence, 1919-1968
ILGWU. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence,
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
ILGWU. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence, 1919-1968
5780/023
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
41 linear feet
Correspondence, speeches.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, speeches, and subject files covering Luigi Antonini's activities, both within and outside of the ILGWU, from the 1920s to the 1960s.
ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the “new unionism,” the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers’ strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers’ strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the “protocol of peace,” a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Local 89 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Italian Dressmakers' Union, was chartered in 1919 and based in New York, New York. Luigi Antonini, garment worker, labor and political leader, and official of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Luigi Antonini was born in Vallata Irpina, Italy, in 1883. After serving in the Italian army, he emigrated to the United States in 1908. He joined the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) in 1913, and was elected to the executive board of Local 25 the following year. A skilled organizer and leader, he was voted a vice president of the ILGWU in 1925, and became First Vice-President in 1934, a position he held for over thirty years.
Antonini was a founding member of the Anti-Fascist Alliance and president of the Italian-American Labor Council. He was also chairman of the American Labor Party and was one of the founders of the Liberal Party of New York. He served on a number of boards and advisory commissions, public and private, during World War II. Antonini remained active in union and political matters until his death in 1968.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, speeches, and subject files covering Luigi Antonini's activities, both within and outside of the ILGWU, from the 1920s to the 1960s.
Individuals and organizations represented in the collection include: August Bellanca; David Dubinsky; Fania Cohn; Giuseppe Faravelli; John F. Kennedy; Fiorello LaGuardia; Jay Lovestone; Guiseppe Modigliani; Franklin Roosevelt; Giuseppe Saragat; Norman Thomas; Harry S. Truman; Gus Tyler; Robert F. Wagner, Jr.; locals and joint boards of the ILGWU; the AFL-CIO; the Confederazione italiana sindacati lavoratori; the Italian-American Labor Council; the Textile Workers' Union of America; Unity House (the ILGWU workers' resort); and the Women's Trade Union League.
The correspondence documents many of Antonini's most significant contributions to the ILGWU, the post-war Italian labor movement, and politics in New York State and the U.S. Included in the collection are materials relating to Antonini's role in the ILGWU, especially in union administrative matters; documentation of his involvement in building a free labor movement in post-war Italy; items dealing with his activities in the American Labor Party and the Liberal Party of New York; and items that highlight his role in anti-fascist organizations before and during the Second World War.
SUBJECTS
Names:
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Antonini, Luigi, 1893-1968.; Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968.; Bellanca, August.; Cohn, Fannia M.(Fannia Mary), 1885-; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Faravelli, Giuseppe.; Kennedy, John F.(John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; La Guardia, Fiorello H.(Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Lovestone, Jay.; Modigliani, Giuseppe Emanuele, 1872-1947.; Nenni, Pietro, 1891-1980.; Roosevelt, Franklin D.(Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Saragat, Giuseppe.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tyler, Gus.; Wagner, Robert F.(Robert Ferdinand), 1910-1991.; AFL-CIO.; American Labor Party.; Confederazione italiana sindacati lavoratori.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Italian-American Labor Council.; Liberal Party of New York State.; Textile Workers Union of America.; Unity House.; Women's Trade Union League.
Subjects:
Anti-fascist movements.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing trade--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Italian Americans.; Labor movement--Italy--20th century.; Labor unions--Italy.; Labor union locals--United States.
Places:
Italy--Politics and government--1922-1945.; Italy--Politics and government--1945-1976.; New York (State)--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Form and Genre Terms:
Correspondence; Organization files; Speeches
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
RELATED MATERIALS
5780. ILGWU Records
5780/024. Local 89 records
5780/064. Local 89 minutes
5780/213. Local 89-22-1 records
NOTES
"Permanent deposit"
SERIES LIST
Series I. Incoming letters, 1924-1925.
Series II. Correspondence, 1933-1965.
Series III. Speeches, 1935-1948.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Incoming letters, 1924-1925.
  - Incoming letters., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    April 1924-Feb. 1925.
  - Incoming letters., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    March-June 1925.
  - Incoming letters., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    July-Dec. 1925.
  - A: Gen. Correspondence., 1938-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Affiliated Dept., 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II. Correspondence, 1933-1965.
  - Aliens., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with public officials and Antonini memorandum on problem of aliens of enemy nationalities during the war and Franklin D. Roosevelt's reply.
  - Alto Adige Controversy., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Correspondence re the implementation of "De Gasperi- Gruber Agreement" bet. Austria and Italy which deals with the treatment by the Italians of the German-speaking minority that live in the Trentino-Alto-Adige region.
  - American Committee for Italian Democracy., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Committee on Italian Migration., 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence with Juvenal Marchisio and Rev. Caesar Donanzan on immigration problems and cases.
  - American Committee on Italian Migration., 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations., 1934-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Labor Party., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, news releases, reports and minutes of various committees.
  - American Labor Party., 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Labor Party., 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Labor Party. Antonini testimonial dinner., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Labor Party. District clubs., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Labor Party. Election of Party candidates., 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    FDR ltr., 1941.
  - American Red Cross., 1942-1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Relief for Italy, Inc., 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Relief for Italy, Inc., 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary, Local 89, Fifteenth., 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary, Local 89, Twentieth., 1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary, Local 89, Thirtieth., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary, "Voice of Local 89," Thirtieth., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - A.N.S.A. (Italian National News Agency, Inc.)., 1951-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Birthday greetings and birthday celebrations., 1942-1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Birthday greetings and celebrations., 1955-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Dinner-dance in honor of Antonini., 1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Costanzo, Joseph., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Condolences on death of brother-in-law, Nov. 1953.
  - Antonini, Luigi. Deceased, Dec. 1968. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Music score., 1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    1945-Aug. 1946
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Sept.-Dec. 1946
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Jan.-July 1947
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Aug. -Dec. 1947
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Antonini, Luigi. Personal Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Association to Aid Children, Italy (ARPI). (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - B: Gen. Correspondence, 1939-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - B: Gen. Correspondence, 1952-1964 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica., 1946-1959 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bellanca, August., 1941-1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bises, Arnold., 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Contributions sent to Bises to be distributed to various Italian causes.
  - Boys' Town of Italy, Inc., 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, IALC., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, IALC., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - By-laws and Statement of Principles, IALC., 1941-1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - C: Gen. Correspondence., 1940-1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - C: Gen. Correspondence., 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - C: Gen. Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Caccamo, Francesca., 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Committee, Union., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - CARE (paccki dono)., 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Thank-you ltrs. on receiving packages.
  - Carrara, Mario., 1954-1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Correspondence re elections and political activities in Foligno, Italy.
  - Cases, Grievance Board. A-B., 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Arranged alphabetically by firm (some by surname).
  - Cases, Grievance Board. Joseph Bruno., 1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. C-D., 1933-1936 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. E-F., 1933-1937 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. G-J., 1934-1937 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. K-L., 1933-1936 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. M-N., 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. O-R., 1934-1937 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. S-T., 1934-1937 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cases, Grievance Board. U-Z., 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Cases, District Cases, Appeal Board, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Cases, District Cases, Grievance Board, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cases, Ettore Frisina and Domenico Trombetta, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cases, Ettore Frisina and Domenico Trombetta, 1934-1936 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Cases, Joseph (Giuseppe) Mangano, 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cases, Joseph (Giuseppe) Mangano, 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cases, Joseph (Giuseppe) Mangano, 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cases, Joseph (Giuseppe) Mangano, 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cases, Vincent Fazio., 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Celebration. Congratulatory messages on anti-Communist victory in the Italian elections., 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Cesari, Vasco., 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Correspondence on labor and political matters in Italy.
  - Chieti (musical band in Italy). IALC contribution to band., 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Cilia, Nicola., 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Circulars, Communist Party (n.d.). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - City of Hope (Los Angeles Sanatorium)., 1937-1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Claims against Local for benefits., 1948-1960 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Coli, Gianfranco., 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Includes Correspondence on aiding Coli establish a polio clinic in Rome.
  - Columbus Citizens Committee (for Columbus Day parade)., 1939-1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Committee for a Just Peace with Italy, Inc., 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Committee to Defend America., 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Complaints and Investigations., 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Complaints and Investigations., 1940-1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings., 1943-1946 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Includes Correspondence, reports, resolutions and declarations at annual and general meetings, congratulatory messages.
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1949-1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1953-1956 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, IALC Annual Meetings, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Consoni, Paolo: 1951-56. Includes, 1951-1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Correspondence on labor and political situation in Italy.
  - Contributions to Organizations and Individuals, 1938-1940 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Contributions to Organizations and Individuals, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Contributions to Organizations and Individuals, 1943-1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Conventions, Union., 1937-1950 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Includes resolutions submitted by local.
  - Cooperative Movement in Italy (Lega Nazionale delle Cooperative)., 1945-1957 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Includes ltrs. from Enrico Dugoni informing Antonini of activities in rebuilding cooperatives in Italy.
  - Corriere Degli Italiani, Argentina., 1950 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Corriere del Popolo, Calif., 1947-1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    I.c.w. Carmelo Zito.
  - Corsi, Edward, 1955-1959. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Cotiilo, Salvatore A., 1935-1938. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Council of Golden Ring Clubs, 1958-1960. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Crespi, Cesare, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - D: Gen. Correspondence, 1943-1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - De Gasperi, Alcide., 1945-1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Includes Correspondence re De Gasperi 's visit to U.S.A., 1947.
  - Dinner tendered by IALC in honor of Adolph A. Berle, Jr., 1942 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Nov. 1942.
  - Dinner tendered by IALC in honor of Manlio Brosio., 1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    May 1961.
  - Dinner tendered by IALC in honor of Giovanni Gronchi., 1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    March 1956.
  - Dinner tendered by Segni-Pella Dinner Committee in honor of Antonio Segni., 1959-1964 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Dinner tendered by IALC in honor of Count Carlo Sforza., 1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    April 1949.
  - DiNola, Jack, 1950-1951. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - DiStefano, Mario, 1951-1952. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - District Corres, Main District, 1939-1960. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Districts, Bensonhurst and Boro Park, 1939-1964. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Districts, Brownsville, 1948-1964. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Districts, Bronx, Harlem, 1939-1964. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Districts, Popular Branch, 1941-1959. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Districts, Pressers' Branch, 1939-1964. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Districts, Williamsburg, 1939-1961. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Dulci, Giuseppe. (Italian newspaper editor)., 1951-1964 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Correspondence on Italian political situation and contributions for political activities in Trieste.
  - E: Gen. Correspondence, 1943-1958 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration., 1949-1955 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with Thomas A. Lane (Labor Attache, American Embassy) on labor and political matters in Italy.
  - Educational Dept. Local 89, 1954-1955. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Einaudi, Luigi, 1949-192. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Election and Installation of Local Officers., 1934-1937 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Includes Examination Committee report.
  - Election and Installation of Local Officers, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Election and Installation of Local Officers, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Election and Installation, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Election and Installation. (Cont.), 1947 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Election and Installation, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Election and Installation of Local Officers, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Election and Installation of Local Officers, 1958-1964. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Election Leaflets. (Various locals) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board. Correspondence and excerpts of early minutes., 1919-1941 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board. Correspondence, 1942-1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - F: Gen. Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - F: Gen. Correspondence., 1953-1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Faraboli, Giovanni., 1936-1945 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Italian Socialist Party-in-exile (Partito Socialista Italiano-Federazione Regionale del Sud-Ouest "Giacomo Matteotti, "Toulouse, France) and with Comite Confederal du Sud-Ouest pour l'Assistance Syndicale (CGT) on solidarity and relief
  - Faraboli, Giovanni., 1947-1953 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Faravelli, Giuseppe., 1936-1946 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Includes requests for financial assistance to various Socialist groups; ltr. from Matteo Matteotti (sighed with other members of Federation) on results of Young Socialist Federation (Federazione Giovanile del Partito Socialista Italiano) meeting, August 1
  - Faravelli, Giuseppe., 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    1947-Mar. 1948. Correspondence on causes and result of split between the Italian Socialist Party (PSI, Partito Socialista Italiano) and Socialist Party of Italian Workers (PSLI, Partito Socialista dei Lavoratori Italiani) from the Italian Socialist Party
  - Faravelli, Giuseppe., 1948-1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    April 1948-56.
  - Fascism, Anti-., 1929-1936 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    I.c.w. anti-Fascist organizations and ltrs. from Fascist organizations and individuals re Italy.
  - Fascism, Anti-., 1937-1948 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Fascism, Anti-. Re Spain., 1936-1951 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Ferrero-Sallitto Defense Conference., 1935-1938 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Correspondence re fight against their (Vincento Ferrero and Domenick Sallitto) deportation.
  - Fierro Memorial Committee. Antonio Fierro., 1934-1937 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Fight for Freedom Committee to Defend America., 1941 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Brazil., 1947-1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    I.c.w. Trento Tagliaferri.
  - Foreign Correspondence, France., 1936-1949 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Italy., 1944 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    (Many ltrs. dispersed throughout collection) Includes ltrs. dealing with relief packages sent to Italy.
  - Foreign Correspondence, Italy., 1946 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Italy., 1945-1964 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Foreign, Italy. Flour distributed through the Italian Red Cross., 1942-1948 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Foreign, Italy. Flour donated by Local 80, distributed through the Italian Red Cross., 1948 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Foreign, Italy. Correspondence re medicine and medical implements sent to Italy through the IALC., 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Foreign, Italy. Re medicine and medical implements., 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Foreign, Italy. Re medicine and medical implements. (cont.), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Foreign, Italy. Re medicine and medical implements., 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Foreign, Italy. Medicine and medical implements., 1952-1954 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances (many through the Italian Red Cross)., 1945-1949 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Foreign, Italy, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1950 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1950 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1951 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1951 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1951 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1952 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1952 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1953 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1953 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1955 (Box 21, Folder 6)